A Guide to the State Council of Higher Education for Virginia. Office of the Director. Subject and Correspondence Files, 1974-1997
Library of Virginia
- Series II: Speeches and Writings, 1974-1997
  - Subseries 1: Speeches given by Dr. Davies, 1975-1997
    - Thomas Nelson Community College, August 16, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Virginia Community College System Instructional Leadership Seminar, August 17, 1988 (see box 8 folder 9, legal size)
    - College of William and Mary, Education in the Commonwealth, September 9, 1988 (see box 8 folder 10, legal size)
    - Norfolk Collegiate School, September 11, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Commission on the University of the 21st Century, September 19, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Governor's Professor of the Year Award (South Carolina), October 11, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - College of William and Mary Public Policy Conference, October 28, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Annual Conference on Undergraduate Student Assessment, November 3, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Conference for Potential Graduate Students, November 3, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - SCHEV General Education Conference, December 2, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Liberal Studies Career Forum, James Madison University, February 15, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Hollins College Founder's Day Convocation, February 23, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Old Dominion University, March 20, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Virginia Commonwealth University, March 31, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Bridgewater College Founder's Day Academic Convocation, March 31, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Conference on Understanding Change in the Humanities, University of Virginia, April 14, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - EACUBO 6th Annual Chief Business Officers Institute: Managing the Cost of Higher Education, April 16, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Rocco Forum for the Future of Learning for Life, April 18, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Outstanding Faculty Awards Ceremony, May 9, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Trinity Episcopal School, June 3, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - High Point College (NC), June 29, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Rappahannock Community College, August 16, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Mary Washington College Faculty Meeting, August 24, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - SCHEV Conference for Potential Graduate Students, November 3, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - College of William and Mary Orientation Session for New Members of the General Assembly, December 1, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Better Information Project, December 7, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - American Association for Higher Education, April 3, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - SCHEV Statewide Conference on Improving Human Relationships on College Campuses, April 6, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - AAUP April 6, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Lynchburg College, April 7, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Va. Association of Black Faculty and Administrators in Higher Education, April 9, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Shenandoah College and Conservatory Faculty Retreat, April 16, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Roast of Dr. Gordon K. Davies April 17, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - State Higher Education Board Members First Regional Conference, April 23, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Minnesota College and University System, April 24, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Association of Research Libraries, May 10, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Academic Advising in Virginia, May 11, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Governor's Commission on Educational Opportunity for all Virginians, May 14, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Institute of Higher Education, June 27, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - ECS National Forum and Annual Meeting, July 12, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - Governor's Conference on Education, July 24, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - National Association of Schools and Colleges of the United Methodist Church, July 30, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - United Methodist Church Board of Higher Education, July 31, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - State Higher Education Executive Officers Association Annual Meeting, Aug. 1990 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Northern Va. Community College, Aug. 1990 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Project Internationsl Emphasis, Aug. 9, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Old Dominion University Inaugural Dinner of President James Koch, Sept. 13, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - Va. Women's Studies Association, Oct. 20, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - Va. PTA/PTSA Convention, Nov. 2, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - Metro Leadership Program, Richmond, Nov. 7, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - Statewide Conference on Black Student Retention, Nov. 29, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - Va. Beach Development Authority Annual Meeting, Dec. 7, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - Inter American University of Puerto Rico, Jan. 9, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - Association of Va. Colleges and Universities, Jan. 22, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - Western Maryland College Annual Faculty Conference, Jan. 25, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 104)
    - Enhancing the Quality of Teaching, Feb. 1, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 105)
    - American Council on Education National Identification Program, Feb. 1, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 106)
    - Roast of Donal S. Beyer, Jr., March 13, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 107)
    - Conference on International Competitiveness, Radford University, April 5, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 108)
    - SHEEO/SREB Regional Meeting for Board Members, April 15, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 109)
    - Va. College Placement Association, April 26, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - The College of Applied Science, James Madison University, May 6, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - Piedmont Va. Community College Commencement, May 10, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - Academic Leadership Conference, June 6, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - SREB State Policy and Productivity in Higher Education, July 2, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 114)
    - Project International Emphasis Institute, July 12, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 115)
    - Va. Council for International Education, Oct. 3, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - Richmond Rotary Club, Oct. 8, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - Va. Wesleyan College Fall Convocation, Oct. 15, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 118)
    - National Assoc. of State Universities, Nov. 11, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 119)
    - World AIDS Day, Dec. 2, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 120)
    - Eastern Assoc. of College and University Business Officers, March 19, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 121)
    - Improving Human Relations on College Campuses, April 3, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 122)
    - Outstanding Faculty Awards, May 12, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 123)
    - Leadership Hampton Roads, June 4, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 124)
    - National Commission on Responsibilites for Financing Postsecondary Education, June 16, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 125)
    - Roanoke Valley Education Consortium, Oct. 20, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 126)
    - Va. Commonwealth University Graduate School Retreat, Oct. 23, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 127)
    - Va. Assoc. for Management Analysis and Planning, Nov. 6, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 128)
    - Annual Conference on Student Assessment, Nov. 12-13, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 129)
    - Conference for Potential Graduate Students, Nov. 13, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 130)
    - Leadership Fairfax Education Program, Jan. 14, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 131)
    - AAHE Conf. on Faculty Roles and REwards, Jan. 29, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 132)
    - Va. Quality Education in Sciences and Technology, Feb. 5, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 133)
    - Campus Sexual Assault Conference, Feb. 10, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 134)
    - American's Investment in Liberal Education, College of William and Mary, Feb. 11, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 135)
    - Richmond Kiwanis Club, March 8, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 136)
    - NIH Staff Training in Extramural Program, March 18, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 137)
    - Va. Social Science Association, March 27, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 138)
    - Conference on Metropolitan Universities, March 30, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 139)
    - NCSCBHEP Annual Conference, April 20, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 140)
    - Jessie Ball duPont Fund Lifetime Achievement Award, Apr. 30, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 141)
    - Conf. of World Class Education, May 4, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - Mary Washington College Commencement, May 8, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 143)
    - Lafayette High School, Williamsburg, Va., May 28, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 144)
    - American Assoc. of State Colleges and Universities, June 6, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 145)
    - George Mason University Faculty Colloquium, Setp. 22, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 146)
    - Lunch et Veritas, Oct. 21, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - Va. Commonwealth University, University Honors Program, Oct. 22, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 148)
    - VAMAP, Nov. 6, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Commonwealth Center for Literary and Cultural Change, Univ. of Va., Feb. 24, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 150)
    - Forum on Higher Education, Lynchburg College, Apr. 16, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 151)
    - Va. Foundation of Independent Colleges, Apr. 19, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 152)
    - Eastern Va. Medical School Commencement, May 21, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 153)
    - National University Teleconference Network Conference, July 17, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 154)
    - Virginia Community Colleges Association Annual Meeting Oct. 6, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Annual Meeting of Academic Officers - Pennsylvania State System of Higher Education Oct. 13, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Southern Regional Congress of Health Professions Educators, Oct. 17, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Joint Task Force on UMass. and Community College Relations, Nov. 29, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Association of College Honor Societies, Feb. 18, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Annual Conference of the National Center for the Study of Collective Bargaining in Higher Education Apr. 24, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Shenandoah University Commencement May 13, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - National Learning Infrastructure Initiative Conference, June 19, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Instructional Leadership Seminar Virginia Community College System Aug. 17, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - National center on Postsecondary Teaching, Learning and Assessment - Policy Seminar on Assessment in Higher Education Oct. 31, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Southern Regional Education Board Legislative Advisory Council Nov. 11, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Virginia College Health Center Conference, Nov. 13, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Joint Education Oversight Committee North Carolina General Assembly Nov. 16, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Virginia Commonwealth University Medical College of Virginia Department of Family Practice 25th Anniversary Celebration Nov. 18, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Ferrum College Commencement, May 5, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Virtual Library of Virginia (VIVA) Retreat, June 12, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Richmond Rotary Club Sept. 17, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - American Association of Colleges and Universities, Oct. 26, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Virginia Business Council, Nov. 7, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Hollins College Inauguration of Dr. Janet E. Rasmussen Nov. 7, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - University of Virginia Curry School of Education Rotunda Dinner Nov. 22, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Board of Visitors Conference, March 10, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Virginia Business Higher Education Council Symposium April 13, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Speeches and Writings by Gordon K. Davies, Date or Event Unknown (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Writings and presentations, author unknown, 1986-1995 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Subseries 2: Speeches given by others, 1977-1992
    Arranged chronologically within folders. Contains speeches given by members of the SCHEV staff and members of Virginia government, as well as other individuals. Some of the speeches were written by Dr. Davies for others, although authorship is not always stated.
    - Speeches given by H. Merrill Pasco, SCHEV Chairman, 1977-1980 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Speeches given by others, 1978-1992 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Subseries 3: Writings and Publications, 1974-1997
    Arranged chronologically by date of creation or publication, whichever is noted. Contains articles and reviews written by Dr. Davies, both published and unpublished.
    - The Search for Center: Religious Study and Autobiography, Sept. 18, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - The Afternoon of Life: A Proposal for a New Kind of Adult Education, July 14, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - The Conflict Between Quantity and Quality, June 1978 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Graduate Education: Access, Quality, and Competition, August 1979 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - How Virginia's Colleges and Universities Can Shape Up the System, Jan. 31, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - School, College Links Key to Educational Goals, May 21, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - State Higher Education Agencies and Continuing Education, July 1982 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - High Tech and the Social Responsibilities of Higher Education, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - An Assessment: Where Virginia Stands on Higher Education, Nov. 27, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - A Proposal to Study the Changing Nature of Jobs in Virginia, Dec. 8, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Cooperative Education: A State-Level View, Winter 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Babel or Opportunity? Recent Reports on Education, Winter 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Opinion: 2 ways of Seeing Colleges' Needs, Jan. 6, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - A Program to Ensure Educational Opportunity to Virginia's Workforce, Spring 1984 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - 42. Book Review, Conflict in Higher Education: State Government Coordination Versus Institutional Independence, April 1984 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Degree Program Productivity Report, July 19, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Keep Liberal Arts in College Curricula, July 20, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Proposal for Essay in Handbook on Higher Education, Aug. 30, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Honoring the Spiritual and Practical (Tobacco, Souls and the Aims of Education), Sept. 21, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Review and Comment on Involvement and Learning, the National Institute for Education Report on Higher Education, Nov. 13, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Virginia Higher Education: Out in Front, Winter 1985 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Virginia's Capital Investment: Higher Education, April 4, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Alternative Funding Strategies for Higher Education, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - General Threats to Institutional Integrity, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Flipping the Paradigm: Questioning International Competition, Sept. 8, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - 53. Ten Years of Higher Education in Virginia: a Report to the State Council of Higher Education for Virginia, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Fall Enrollment by Race at Virginia's Public Institutions: Men vs. Women, Feb. 20, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - The Future of the Humanities in Virginia Higher Education, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - The President's Bold Educational Reform Is a Scam, May 15, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Bush's Better-Schools Scam, June 1, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Colleges and Universities for the 21st Century, July 10, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - 59. Book Review: The Moral Collapse of the University: Professionalism, Purity, and Alienation, July/August 19991 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Virginia must invest more in its colleges, Oct. 16, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - A Script change for higher education, April 5, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Crisis in Higher Education, July 7, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - The Collapse of the Cold War University, July 9, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Higher Education's Mandate: Virginia Voters Did Not Flash Green Light to Indiscipline, Nov. 11, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Accommodating Enrollment Growth in Virginia, Nov. 25, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Colleges are: (a) Precious Asset, (b) Creaky Relic, (c) Both, Sept. 30, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Make a good system better: Don't flush away years of higher-ed progress, Oct. 6, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Another view: Don't forget higher education strength, Oct. 7, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Leadership and Public Choice, Winter 1994 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Increased Support: Colleges Should Repay Good Deeds by Assembly, March 19, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - For our sake, affirmative action needs new strategies, May 12, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - The Athenian Flaw: Reform, don't jettison, affirmative action, May 13, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Statewide planning in Virginia's higher education, nd (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Muddled priorities on loan defaults, nd (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Book Review: An Idea by Elizabeth Sewell, nd (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - Subseries 4: Source Materials for Writings and Speeches, 1930-1996
    Arranged alphabetically by folder title. Contains published materials found in Dr. Davies' files that appear to have been retained as source material for his articles and speeches. Arrangement was determined, in part, by the original order of the collection. Articles arranged in alphabetical order and by subject were maintained in these orders by Dr. Davies. Other materials are arranged by publication date.
    - Articles, 1955-1978 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - Articles, 1979-1968 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - Articles, 1987-1996 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - Articles, A-H (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - Articles, I-P (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - Articles, Q-Z (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - Articles and other materials (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - Conflict in Higher Education: State Government versus Institutional Independence by John D. Millett (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Conflict in Higher Education: State Government versus Institutional Independence by John D. Millett (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Health Care Reform (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Health Care Reform (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Health Care Reform (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Articles, Political correctness (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Series III: External Activities, 1987-1996
  Comprised of five (5) subseries: Kentucky Centers of Excellence and Endowed Chairs; State of Louisiana -- Desegregation Settlement Agreement Monitoring Committee; Virginia Commonwealth University, University Honors Program; Mary Sue Terry Gubernatorial Campaign, and Nepal. Contains correspondence, clippings and other materials related to Dr. Davies' activities outside of SCHEV as a consultant and educator.
  - Subseries 1: Kentucky Centers of Excellence and Endowed Chairs, 1987-1993
    Arranged chronologically by date. Contains correspondence, notes and reports generated by the committee formed by the Kentucky Council on Higher Education to investigate the procedures and effectiveness of the Kentucky Centers of Excellence and the Endowed Chairs Program.
    - Evaluation of Kentucky Centers of Excellence and Endowed Chairs, fo. 1 of 7 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Evaluation of Kentucky Centers of Excellence and Endowed Chairs, fo. 2 of 7 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Evaluation of Kentucky Centers of Excellence and Endowed Chairs, fo. 3 of 7 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Evaluation of Kentucky Centers of Excellence and Endowed Chairs, fo. 4 of 7 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Evaluation of Kentucky Centers of Excellence and Endowed Chairs, fo. 5 of 7 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Evaluation of Kentucky Centers of Excellence and Endowed Chairs, fo. 6 of 7 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Evaluation of Kentucky Centers of Excellence and Endowed Chairs, fo. 7 of 7 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 2: State of Louisiana-Desegration Settlement Agreement Monitoring Committee, 1988-1996
    Arranged chronologically by date. Contains correspondence, notes and reports generated by the three-member committee formed by Louisiana Board of Regents to ensure the compliance of the State of Louisiana in regards to the ruling of the United States Supreme Court.
    - State of Louisiana -- Desegregation Settlement Agreement Monitoring Committee, fo. 1 of 7 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - State of Louisiana -- Desegregation Settlement Agreement Monitoring Committee, fo. 2 of 7 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - State of Louisiana -- Desegregation Settlement Agreement Monitoring Committee, fo. 3 of 7 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - State of Louisiana -- Desegregation Settlement Agreement Monitoring Committee, fo. 4 of 7 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - State of Louisiana -- Desegregation Settlement Agreement Monitoring Committee, fo. 5 of 7 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - State of Louisiana -- Desegregation Settlement Agreement Monitoring Committee, fo. 6 of 7 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - State of Louisiana -- Desegregation Settlement Agreement Monitoring Committee, fo. 7 of 7 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Subseries 3: Virginia Commonwealth University, University Honors Program, 1989-1990
    Arranged chronologically. Contains materials used in preparing the course Dr. Davies taught at Virginia Commonwealth University (VCU) in the University Honors Program during the 1989/90 school year titled, Continuity and Change.
    - Virginia Commonwealth University, University Honors Program, 1989/90 Course Materials (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Subseries 4: Mary Sue Terry Gubernatorial Campaign, 1990-1993
    Arranged chronologically by date. Contains correspondence, notes, position papers and reports related to Ms. Terry's gubernatorial campaign in 1993.
    - Mary Sue Terry Gubernatorial Campaign, 1990-1993 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Subseries 5: Nepal, 1991-1996
    Arranged chronologically by date. Contains correspondence, notes and other materials related to Dr. Davies' visit to Nepal as a member of a National Governor's Association team to assist officials in Nepal identify possible improvements to the Nepalese higher education system.
    - National Governors' Association Center for Policy Research, Nepal (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Series IV: Termination of Director of SCHEV, 1997
  Divided into three subseries: correspondence; clippings; and notes. All subseries are arranged chronologically. Includes correspondence, memos, newspaper accounts, and other materials relating to the April 1997 action of the Council to not renew Dr. Davies' contract.
  - Subseries 1: Correspondence, 1996-1997
    Arranged chronologically by date. Contains correspondence with the Council before and after the Council's decision to not renew Dr. Davies' contact and letters to Dr. Davies regarding the action taken by the Council.
    - Correspondence re: Gordon K. Davies' departure, April - July 1997 -- fo. 1 of 4 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence re: Gordon K. Davies' departure, April - July 1997 -- fo. 2 of 4 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence re: Gordon K. Davies' departure, April - July 1997 -- fo. 3 of 4 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence re: Gordon K. Davies' departure, April - July 1997 -- fo. 4 of 4 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence with Council, 1996-1997, fo. 1 of 2 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Council, 1996-1997, fo. 2 of 2 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 2: Clippings, 1996-1997
    Arranged chronologically by date of publication. Contains newspaper and other clippings from publications relating to the events leading up to the non-renewal of Dr. Davies' contract.
    - Press clippings, 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 3: Notes, 1996-1997
    - Notes, 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Series V: Gordon K. Davies
  Arranged alphabetically by folder title. Contains biographical information about Dr. Davies.
  - Curriculum Vitae (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, ca. 1998 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Series VI: Miscellaneous Materials
  Arranged alphabetically by folder title. Contains materials related to Dr. Davies' activities inside and outside of SCHEV.
  - 1984/85 Statistics: NIE Study Analysis (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - The Continuum of Education Response to House Joint Resolution No. 211, Appropriations Act Item 157 and House Joint Resolution No. 142 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Council Restructuring, 1994 - 1995 -- fo. 1 of 2 (Box 7, Folder 9)